<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text Mining on What I talk about when I don&#39;t talk about me</title>
    <link>/tags/text-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text Mining on What I talk about when I don&#39;t talk about me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 02:04:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/text-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Yelp ratings using textual reviews</title>
      <link>/2014/12/30/predicting-yelp-ratings-using-textual-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 02:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/30/predicting-yelp-ratings-using-textual-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Internet is truly full of free and fascinating datasets! I found this Yelp Dataset Challenge the other day that includes, among others, over 1 million reviews (most of which are recent) along with their respective 5-star ratings - excellent text mining material! Although to enter the competition (which ends on 12/31/14), you have to be a current student (which I&amp;rsquo;m not), but everyone is welcome to play around with the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random acts of pizza - a Kaggle competition</title>
      <link>/2014/08/19/random-acts-of-pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 06:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/08/19/random-acts-of-pizza/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, I participated in a Kaggle not-for-prize competition that uses data obtained from Reddit&amp;rsquo;s Random Acts of Pizza forum to analyze and predict the outcome of a request for pizza, and it was heaps of fun (I always wanted to say that)! Compared with other Kaggle competitions I had tried before, I found this one a bit easier because the dataset is not very large (~5,000 records) and is hence perfect for model experimenting, and, more importantly, the competition is based on a real research done by a couple Stanford researchers, which provides me with a lot of guidelines in how to proceed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>