<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rnn on What I talk about when I don&#39;t talk about me</title>
    <link>/tags/rnn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rnn on What I talk about when I don&#39;t talk about me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rnn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do I really need attention in my seq2seq model?</title>
      <link>/2018/12/19/do-i-really-need-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/19/do-i-really-need-attention/</guid>
      <description>Background Since the origin of the idea of attention (Bahdanau et al., 2015), it has become a norm to try to insert it in a seq2seq model, especially in translations. It is such an intuitive and powerful idea (not to mention the added benefit of peaking into an otherwise blackbox model) that many tutorials and blog posts made it sound like one should not even bother with a model without it as the results would for sure be inferior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Language Acquisition Modeling using Duolingo&#39;s Data</title>
      <link>/2018/11/26/second-language-acquisition-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/26/second-language-acquisition-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Background Recently, I have discovered the Second Language Acquisition Modeling (SLAM) challenge hosted by Duolingo earlier this year, where they had asked the participants to predict the per-token error rate for a given language learner based on his/her past learning history. To conclude the competition, the team has also written a paper to summarize the results and the approaches that were taken by the various participants and their respective effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second attempt at building a language translator</title>
      <link>/2017/09/07/second-attempt-at-building-a-language-translator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/07/second-attempt-at-building-a-language-translator/</guid>
      <description>Background A few weeks ago, I experimented with building a language translator using a simple sequence-to-sequence model. Since then, I had been itchy to add an extra attention layer to it that I had been reading so much about. After many, many research, I came across (quite accidentally) this MOOC series offered by fast.ai, where on Lesson 13, instructor Jeremy Howard walked the students through a practical implementation of the attention mechanism using PyTorch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First attempt at building a language translator</title>
      <link>/2017/08/14/first-attempt-at-building-a-language-translator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/14/first-attempt-at-building-a-language-translator/</guid>
      <description>Background After having tried my hands on LSTM and built a text generater, I became interested in the sequence-to-sequence models, particularly their applications in language translations. It all started with this TensorFlow tutorial where the authors demonstrated how they built an English-to-French translator using such a model and successfully translated &amp;ldquo;Who is the president of the United States?&amp;rdquo; into French with the correct grammar (&amp;ldquo;Qui est le président des États-Unis?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Jane Austen, Oscar Wilde, and F. Scott Fitzgerald walk into a bar</title>
      <link>/2017/07/27/when-jane-austen-oscar-wilde-and-f-scott-fitzgerald-walk-into-a-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/27/when-jane-austen-oscar-wilde-and-f-scott-fitzgerald-walk-into-a-bar/</guid>
      <description>Background Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time learning about deep learning, particularly its applications in natural language processing, a field I have been immensely interested in. Before deep learning, my foray into NLP has been mainly about sentiment analysis1 and topic modeling.2 These projects are fun but they are all limited in analyzing an existing corpus of text whereas I&amp;rsquo;m also interested in applications that generate texts themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>