<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life Story on What I talk about when I don&#39;t talk about me</title>
    <link>/tags/life-story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life Story on What I talk about when I don&#39;t talk about me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/life-story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My month of unemployment</title>
      <link>/other-musings/my-month-of-unemployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/other-musings/my-month-of-unemployment/</guid>
      <description>On September 10, 2019, I lost my job in a mass layoff. Now, after having endured a month-long unemployment, fortunately concluded by signing another job offer today, I decided to sit down and retrospectively document my journey, which, although arguably small and inconsequential in the grand scheme of things, was important and transformative for me. As the cliché goes, you learn a lot about yourself when going through obstacles. Indeed, over the span of this month, I have subsequently come to identify my weakness, my insecurity, my solitude, and later, my resilience and my self-worth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s the end of the year, let me talk about myself.</title>
      <link>/other-musings/it-s-the-end-of-the-year-let-me-talk-about-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/other-musings/it-s-the-end-of-the-year-let-me-talk-about-myself/</guid>
      <description>The title says it all.
No, seriously, this post is all about me. So much for not talking about me&amp;hellip;
This may be cliché but, on this very last day of 2018, I want to end the year with a reflection of things that have greatly influenced me this year. These “things” come in various shapes and forms: persons, books, podcasts, courses, events, and YouTube series. Whatever they are, as long as they left a big impression on me and helped me grow, be it personally or professionally, I’m going to list them here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>